让我们回顾一下我们所涉及的一些主题
Let's recap some of the topics we've covered
在这个讲座中。我们首先谈论齐次坐标，一种不同的方式
in this lecture. We started by talking about homogeneous coordinates, a different way to
表示二维平面中的点。我们谈到了转换笛卡儿的方法
represent points in a 2 dimensional plane. We talked about ways to convert Cartesian
坐标到齐次坐标和齐次坐标回到笛卡尔坐标
coordinates to homogeneous coordinates and homogeneous coordinates back to Cartesian
坐标。在数学上，线和点是双重的。
coordinates. Mathematically, lines and points are duals.
这导致了一些非常好的方法来计算两条线或两条线的交点
This leads to some very nice ways to compute the intersection points at 2 lines or the
由2分组成的线。我们讨论了一种不同的透视投影模型
line that is formed by 2 points. We've discussed a different perspective projection model called
中央投影模型和关键区别在于图像平面位于对象之间
the Central Projection Model and the key difference is that the image plane is between the object
原点和它形成一个不倒置的图像。
and the origin and it forms an image that is not inverted.
我们可以使用世界的齐次坐标将其表示为矩阵修改
We can represent this as a matrix modification using homogeneous coordinates of the world
点和图像平面上的点。在真正的数码相机中，图像平面
point and of the point on the image plane. In a real digital camera, the image plane
是一大组光敏元素，它们形成所得图像的像素。
is a large array of light sensitive elements, which form the pixels of the resulting image.
我们需要处理这个图像平面的离散性质，即坐标的事实
We need to deal with the discrete nature of this image plane, the fact that the coordinates
以像素为单位而不是以米为单位进行测量。还有一个起源
are measured in units of pixels rather than in units of metres. There's also an origin
移位涉及而不是像平面的中心，像素坐标中的原点
shift involved instead of the centre of the image plane, the origin in pixel coordinates
在左上角，我们可以通过简单的线性变换来介绍它。
is in the top left corner and we can introduce that with a simple linear transformation.
最终，我们将许多矩阵项组合在一起。前两个我们称之为
Ultimately, we combine a number of matrix terms together. The first 2 we refer to as
相机的内在参数。他们完全按照术语描述了相机
the intrinsic parameters of a camera. They described the camera entirely in terms
它的像素尺寸，主点坐标和焦距
of the dimensions of its pixels, the coordinate of the principal point and the focal length
镜头这些是相机本身的参数。相机在哪里都没关系
of the lens. These are parameters of the camera itself. It doesn't matter where the camera
是或在哪里指向。内在参数对于相机的位置是不变的。
is or where it's pointing. The intrinsic parameters are invariant to the location of the camera.
这个链中的第3个矩阵，我们称之为外在参数，他们描述了
The 3rd matrix in this chain, we refer to as the extrinsic parameters and they described
相机的姿势，它的位置和相对于世界的方向
the pose of the camera that is its position and its orientation with respect to the world's
坐标框架。我们可以将所有这些矩阵组合成一个3乘4的矩阵
coordinate frame. We can combine all these matrices together into a single 3 by 4 matrix
它编码所有信息。因此，从世界点到图像平面的投影
which encodes all that information. So, the projection from the world point to image plane
简单地通过矩阵修改完成点，该矩阵修改为我们提供了齐次坐标
point is done simply by a matrix modification which gives us the homogeneous coordinates
在图像平面上的点和那些同质的之间有一个简单的映射
of the point on the image plane and there is a simple mapping between those homogeneous
坐标和笛卡尔图像平面坐标，我们通常用U和V表示。
coordinates and the Cartesian image plane coordinates which we typically denote by U and V.
该表示是尺度不变的。我们可以乘以相机矩阵
This representation is scale invariant. We can multiply  the camera matrix
通过任意非零常数，投影保持不变。
by an arbitrary non-zero constant and the projection remains unchanged.
该矩阵通常以标准化的方式编写
This matrix is often written in a normalized
元素C34等于1的形式。如果点位于世界的平面上，那么我们
form where element C34 is equal to 1. If the points lie on a plane in the world, then we
可以在平面上的点的坐标和之间写出不同的关系
can write a different relationship between the coordinate of the point on the plane and
图像平面上的点的坐标，我们使用3乘3单应矩阵来做到这一点
the coordinate of the point on the image plane and we use a 3 by 3 homography matrix to do this
Homography矩阵映射平面上的点
Homography matrix maps points from a plane
到另一架飞机。如果我们知道4组相应的，我们就可以计算单应矩阵
to another plane. We can compute the homography matrix if we know 4 sets of corresponding
两架飞机之间的分数。对应表示点P和点Q表示
points between the 2 planes. Corresponding means that the point P and the point Q refer
同一点，世界上同样的特征。
to the same point, the same feature in the world.
单应性的一个应用是计算透视矫正。我们可以计算
One application of homographies is to compute perspective rectification. We can compute
单应性H将点从1个图像中的点P映射到另一个图像中的点Q.
an homography H which maps points from point P in 1 image to point Q in another image and
如果我们正确选择H，我们可以消除透视失真的影响。另一个
if we choose H correctly, we can undo the effect of perspective distortion. Another
单应性的应用是我们可以采用这样的矩形图形并扭曲
application of homographies is that we can take a rectangular graphic like this and distort
它以这样一种方式，似乎完美地放在一个不同的平面上。在这种情况下，
it in such a way that it appears to lay perfectly into a different plane. In this case, the
飞机是游泳池的表面。我们可能的最后一个例子
plane is the surface of the swimming pool. The final example of how we might be able
使用单应性与本课程的项目部分有关，我们可以用它来绘图
to use an homography is related to the project part of this course and we can use it to map
摄像机图像平面中的坐标到机器人上的点的XY坐标
a coordinate in the image plane of the camera to an XY coordinate of a point on the robots
二维工作表。
2 dimensional worksheet.